### Contact

brharrell@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/dr-brad-harrell-91b45913 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Nursing Critical Care Teaching

### Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)

### Certifications

Acute Care Nurse Practitioner Body Language for Leaders Learning to Be Approachable

#### Honors-Awards

Tennessee Nurses Association – State Practice Award Nominee

Leadership Germantown Participant

Tennessee State Representative, American Nurses Association's Inaugural Membership Assembly

Tennessee Nurses Association, State President Nominee

American Nurses Association, Leadership Institute, State-Appointed

#### **Publications**

Analysis of Cricoid Pressure Force and Technique among Anesthesiologists, Nurse Anesthetists, and Registered Nurses

Health Care Providers' Perceptions of Quality of Care: Spiritual Interventions and Medical Missions

Response Times and Sleepiness among Fatigued CRNAs

Identifying the Association Among Risk Factors and Mortality in Trauma Patients With Intra-Abdominal Hypertension and Abdominal Compartment Syndrome

# Dr. Brad Harrell

Director of MSN Programs at Loewenberg College of Nursing Nurse Practitioner, Ripley Medical Clinic

Greater Memphis Area

# Summary

Dr. Brad Harrell is a DNP-prepared acute care nurse practitioner, faculty member, and academic leader. He currently holds an appointment as a Clinical Associate Professor at University of Memphis' Loewenberg College of Nursing. He received a BSN and MSN with an emphasis in nursing education from University of Memphis. He received a Doctor of Nursing Practice with an emphasis in acute/critical care advanced practice from University of Tennessee Health Science Center and is nationally board certified as an Acute Care Nurse Practitioner.

Dr. Harrell was a trauma nurse, nurse educator, charge nurse, and wound care nurse in the trauma center at the Regional Medical Center at Memphis (The MED), now Regional One Health. His doctoral inquiry explored risk factors for abdominal compartment syndrome and their relationship to mortality in trauma patients. He currently practices as an ACNP at Ripley Medical Clinic both in the clinic and by making house calls.

Dr. Harrell teaches undergraduate and graduate nursing programs. He primarily teaches graduate nursing education courses, and undergraduate medical-surgical courses. He has taught pharmacology, pathophysiology, gerontology, leadership, foundations, health assessment and skills.

Dr. Harrell is an active member of the Tennessee Nurses
Association. He currently serves as District 12 President and is a
member of the State Presidents Council. He is an active member of
the American Nurses Association and served as a Content Expert for
the American Nurses Credentialing Center. He currently serves on
the American Association of Colleges of Nursing's Diversity, Equity,
and Inclusion Group.

## Experience

Loewenberg College of Nursing, University of Memphis 5 years

Director of MSN Programs May 2017 - Present (3 years 3 months)

Memphis, Tennessee

Clinical Associate Professor August 2015 - Present (5 years) Memphis, Tennessee, United States

Tennessee Department of Mental Health and Substance Abuse Services Nurse Practitioner, DNP April 2020 - Present (4 months)

Bolivar, Tennessee, United States

Ripley Medical Clinic & Home Visits Nurse Practitioner, DNP May 2014 - Present (6 years 3 months) Ripley, TN

Provide internal medicine and primary care to adults both in the clinic and through requested home visits.

U.S. Department of Veterans Affairs Nurse Practitioner June 2015 - August 2015 (3 months) Memphis, Tennessee

Union University
5 years 8 months
Chair, Undergraduate Nursing
2013 - January 2015 (2 years)
Memphis Regional Campus

Served as leader for nationally-renowned group of nursing faculty at the Germantown campus. Led initiatives related to the undergraduate nursing program and the RN-BSN program.

Tenured Associate Professor June 2009 - January 2015 (5 years 8 months) Taught in undergraduate and graduate programs. Fully engaged in life, learning, and faculty community.

Associate Professor - Tenured June 2009 - January 2015 (5 years 8 months) Memphis, Tennessee

#### **TeamHealth**

Acute Care Nurse Practitioner - DNP September 2010 - June 2014 (3 years 10 months)

Worked as a ER nurse practitioner in large, urban 80-bed ER seeing adult patients of all acuity types and care needs.

### Tennessee Nurses Association

President, District 1

October 2011 - October 2013 (2 years 1 month)

Led non-profit district of the larger Tennessee Nurses Association. This district represents all member nurses of Shelby and Fayette counties. These counties contain over 18,000 working nurse professionals.

University of Tennessee Health Science Center Instructor of Nursing July 2006 - June 2009 (3 years)

Taught didactic and clinical courses in undergraduate program. Worked with DNP program planning committee. Taught inaugural CNL class.

# The Regional Medical Center at Memphis

RN

December 2003 - May 2007 (3 years 6 months)

Worked as trauma staff nurse, wound care nurse, staff development educator, and in trauma administration.

## Education

University of Tennessee-Health Science Center Doctor of Nursing Practice, Nursing (2007 - 2009)

The University of Memphis MSN, Nursing · (2004 - 2006)

The University of Memphis BSN, Nursing · (2001 - 2003)

Dyersburg State Community College N/A, Pre-Nursing/Music · (1999 - 2001)